James Built Software Developer

Web: <u>built.kiwi</u> GitHub: <u>github.com/james-built</u> Email: <u>igbuilt@gmail.com</u> Contact: 021 160 7724

INTRODUCTION

I am a full stack web developer with a diversity of experience behind me, including strong commercial knowledge from my accounting background. I consider myself a lifelong learner, interested in crafting things that have a visible impact on the world around me.

I have also been inspired by the collaborative nature of software development and the strong community that exists around it. My exposure to open source software projects and developer meetups has shown me the excitement and fulfilment on offer when working with others to solve problems using technology.

I love learning new technologies and applying the knowledge I gain to solve problems I see in the world around me. I have found my legal background has given me a strong foundation in thought processes that assist me in doing this, breaking down complex problems into the logical steps required to solve them. Some of the projects I've taken on to develop these abilities are: ALoT (The Auckland Library of Tools), Lunchbunch (2018 Pac. Hack project) Skillshare (collaborative project platform), Coffee Time (coffee roasting assistant). You can find these on my GitHub profile & more information on them at the end of my CV.

PROFICIENCIES

- Full Stack JavaScript Development (Node.js, SQLite, PostgreSQL, Knex, Express, RESTful API design & Redux, React, Babel, Webpack, HTML, CSS)
- Git & GitHub extensive experience working with these tools for managing code
- Application Testing (unit tests, route testing, database testing, component testing)
- Web App Deployment have deployed web apps using Heroku and am presently learning to deploy using the AWS suite
- Agile practical experience working with agile practices in a development team on a number of projects
- **Teamwork** the ability to sense out the needs of a team and act as a facilitator to help bring the best out of everyone's talents
- **Self Awareness** a deep understanding of my own needs and process and how to organise my learning to provide the shortest path to success

EXPERIENCE

Enspiral Dev Academy - Web Development Student

July 2018 - October 2018

- I have just completed the web development bootcamp here, an intensive 9 week course where I learned the technical and non technical skills necessary to build full stack JavaScript web applications in a software development team. This was following more than two months of self directed correspondence learning to prepare for the course which I would do on the weekends and evening after work. In total I have spent ~850 hours training to date.
- The course was more akin to an apprenticeship with a strong focus on learning through doing. I
 had the chance to develop pair programming skills teaming up with a diverse group of students.
 The course also gave me the space to practice my soft skills such as giving and receiving
 feedback, and having difficult conversations.
- We worked on a number of different software projects throughout the course to hone our abilities and got extensive experience with Git & Github for version control, implemented agile practices in

our work, and had the opportunity to develop software for real clients. One as part of the '2018 Pac. Hack', another as part of our final project team up with an Auckland tool library.

Chatfield & Co Ltd Chartered Accountants - Accountant / Auditor

May 2015 - July 2018

- My role here involved preparing financial reporting as well working on the real estate compliance audit for one of the firm's larger clients, Barfoot & Thompson.
- While working on the real estate audit team I helped bring significant efficiencies to the audit
 process through my Excel knowledge, writing custom macro functions in Visual Basic to
 automate much more of the data extraction. Through this I discovered I had an ability and a real
 interest in solving problems with code. I had no prior experience writing code but surprised myself
 how much I could achieve with some persistence, Google, and a logical approach to a problem.

Atlas Copco Ltd - Assistant Accountant

February 2012 - September 2012

Burnsco Marine & Leisure - Sales Assistant

November 2010 - December 2011

EDUCATION

The University of Auckland

2014

• I completed a certificate of proficiency in a number of accounting papers to meet the academic requirements of the NZICA Chartered Accountants Program.

Institute of Professional Legal Studies

2012 - 2013

• I completed my professional legal studies course and was duly enrolled as a Barrister and Solicitor of the High Court of New Zealand in June 2013.

The University of Auckland

2007 - 2011

- Bachelor of Commerce and Law Conjoint
 - o Including Company Law, Tax Law & Intellectual Property papers
- Finance major

INTERESTS

Indoor Cricket

• I have competed in a number of different social teams over the years and hugely enjoy the action and excitement of the sport.

Squash & Tennis

 I've played squash & tennis for many years and had the chance to compete in the men's F grade nationals competition in both 2005 & 2006 having won the Auckland club teams event in both years.

Marathon Running

• I've completed a number of marathon events now just recently completing the 2018 Auckland Half Marathon and I'm now looking to take on a trail marathon.

Motorsport

• I'm a motorsport superfan, closely following Formula 1, MotoGP and a number of other series.

CODING PROJECTS

A few of the projects I have been working on to develop my coding skills are:

ALoT (The Auckland Library of Tools)

www.alot.space

- This project is a fully functioning prototype web app produced as our final project at the Dev Academy Bootcamp. Working in a team of 5 student developers we produced this from concept through to a prototype within a 7 day period.
- The app serves to allow users to rent tools and attend workshops at the Auckland Library of Tools, a concept our team was excited about for its potential to minimise waste, save money and add convenience for users.
- The app has user privileges for administrators & normal users with administrator functions behind protected API routes.
- The front end is built using React, Semantic UI React & CSS Modules for styling, Redux, and Redux Thunk. In the back end we used Node.js, Express, Knex and PostgreSQL. Our user authentication was implemented using Libsodium & JWT. We deployed the app to Heroku and used GitHub for code management as well as project management using the GitHub automated scrum board.
- Developing this app we implemented agile practices in our workflow such as maintaining a
 prioritised backlog on our GitHub project board, rotating responsibility for pull request review
 throughout the week and having regular stand ups & retrospectives to reflect on our process.

Lunchbunch (Pac. Hack 2018)

github.com/nikau-2018/lunchbunch

- We developed this for a product owner who had briefed us on her requirements for a prototype to take her business idea to create nutritious lunches for children further.
- We worked in a dev team with a teach acting as lead developer to guide us through our first experience working with agile processes and showing how to carry out code reviews. It gave me excellent experience working on a development team and really solidified my understanding of Redux.
- Working with a product owner to a design brief was a very useful exercise and having our work contribute to an underserved part of the community was rewarding.

Skillshare (Project Collaboration Platform)

github.com/james-built/skillshare

- This project is one I was working on during the bootcamp to gain familiarity with React, Express & Knex. I intend to take this project further after the course as I've designed it to give me experience working with a more complex data structure than my other projects to date.
- My aim was to create a platform for users with a vision to create something who have a skills or
 equipment gap to be able to connect with others who have the complementary skills/equipment.
- The maker community and sharing economy is growing in New Zealand and these were the
 users I was aiming my app at. The direct inspiration actually came when I noticed that a
 makerspace had been established at the University of Auckland and was thinking of ways I could
 connect with the users of that space.

Coffee Time (Coffee Roasting Assistant)

github.com/james-built/coffee-time

- A personal passion of mine is coffee and I've gone deep enough down the rabbit hole to start home roasting my own beans.
- This project is a work in progress and intended to be a vehicle to teach me some new skills, specifically the Angular framework, CSS theming & GraphQL.
- It will allow me to track roast time and profile based on bean origin as well as adding cupping notes for each roast.